it's Friday October twenty fourth twenty twenty five
今天是10月24日星期五
and this place is buzzing
这个地方很热闹
a popular month to visit
热门月份
what's become a popular place to visit
什么已经成为一个受欢迎的地方
waves of tourists wander the shops
一批批游客在商店里游荡
and restaurants of Kokusai street
和国际街的餐馆
splitting south many then amble into the
向南分裂，然后漫步进入
covered ever vibrant Makiishi public market  it's hot
永远充满活力的牧石公共市场很热
reaching ninety degrees Fahrenheit
达到华氏九十度
or thirty two degrees Celsius
或三十二摄氏度
so many visitors
这么多游客
most hailing from mainland Japan
大多数来自日本大陆
have taken to the island's beautiful beaches or the
去了岛上美丽的海滩
many national and nature parks littering the island
许多国家和自然公园散落在岛上
exploring the comparatively cooler
探索相对凉爽的
climate of the subtropical forest
亚热带森林气候
and they've taken to other islands entirely hopping on
他们已经去了其他岛屿，完全跳上了
ferries to explore the natural beauty of the nearby
渡轮探索附近的自然美景
neighbors  depending on their interests
邻居取决于他们的利益
the tourists spread
游客散开
the foodie rambles the city
美食家在城市里漫步
the free diver heads for the coral lined coast
自由潜水员前往珊瑚海岸
but on an island of only four hundred sixty three
但是在一个只有463人的岛上
square miles or twelve hundred square kilometers or an
平方英里或1200平方公里或
island three fourths the area of Hawaii's Oahu
夏威夷瓦胡岛面积的四分之三
there's only so far the tourists can disperse
游客们只能离开这里
with some seven hundred thousand visitors arriving a month
每月约有70万游客抵达
and a permanent population of one point five million
和一百五十万常住人口
fifty percent larger than Oahu's
比瓦胡岛大百分之五十
this place is always buzzing
这地方总是嗡嗡作响
of course Friday October twenty fourth
当然，10月24日星期五。
twenty twenty five is a bit of a
二十五有点
holiday in itself in the United States
在美国度假本身
Fridays in fall mean high school football
秋天的星期五意味着高中橄榄球
and this school is no different as the KBHS dragons
这所学校和KBHS龙没什么不同
are set to host the Humphrey high school Blackhawks
将主办汉弗莱高中黑鹰队
for a game that will crown a regional champion
这场比赛将加冕地区冠军
now Americans playing American football with
现在美国人玩美式足球
American parents and fans in the stands on a
看台上的美国父母和粉丝
school campus that neighbors a KFC
毗邻肯德基的校园
popeyes and burger king on one side and
一边是大力水手和汉堡王
the suburbs on the other is not novel
另一边的郊区并不新奇
but zoom out
但缩小
this place it turns out is also that place
这个地方原来也是那个地方
the tiny tourist island with the beaches
有海滩的旅游小岛
and both places are in Japan
而且两个地方都在日本
this is Okinawa
这里是冲绳
an island that takes only two hours
一个只需要两个小时的岛
to drive across from tip to tail
从头到尾穿过
and an island that hosts two
和一个容纳两个人的岛屿
entirely different worlds at once
完全不同的世界
this is the core of the American air
这是美国空气的核心
force's presence in the Pacific
部队在太平洋的存在
and all the America that comes with it runs headlong into a
随之而来的所有美国人都一头扎进了
proud distinct culture and a densely populated people
自豪独特的文化和人口稠密的人民
with little wiggle room
几乎没有回旋余地
divergent goals
不同的目标
an imbalance in power
权力不平衡
a complicated history
复杂的历史
and an uncertain future
和不确定的未来
for decades there's been a lot of this  and this  and this
几十年来发生了很多这样这样的事
as worlds and ways of life keep colliding
当世界和生活方式不断碰撞
how things got so hotly contested on this little
事情是如何在这个小小的
island is best summarized by the home of Kuba Saki
岛最好的总结是库巴崎的家
high school's rival Katina high school
高中的竞争对手Katina高中
with seven hundred and seventeen kids enrolled
有717个孩子注册了
it's the largest American high school in Japan
是日本最大的美国高中
largest is a theme here
最大是这里的一个主题
by personnel
按人员
at around twenty thousand
大约两万
Kadena is the largest American Airbase in the Pacific
嘉手纳是美国在太平洋最大的空军基地
the eighteenth wing
第十八翼
which runs the base and is capable of everything
它管理着基地，拥有一切能力
from fighting to resupplying and rescuing
从战斗到补给和救援
has the largest assortment of planes and helicopters
拥有种类最多的飞机和直升机
at around eighty pieces of equipment
大约八十件设备
the wing support group which handles everything from
机翼支持小组处理来自
accommodations and logistics to budgeting recreation and
住宿和后勤到预算娱乐和
mayoral duties of the base is the largest in all the air
基地的市长职责是所有空中最大的
force
力
and the base itself hemmed in by urban Okinawa on both sides
基地本身被冲绳的城市包围
boasts a golf course
拥有一个高尔夫球场
countless parks and sports fields
无数的公园和运动场
and a host of suburban housing developments that from above
和许多郊区住宅开发项目
look like they could be from anywhere in middle America
看起来他们可能来自美国中部的任何地方
how this base ended up as the largest is
这个基地是如何成为最大的基地的
directly linked to the event that gave
直接链接到给的事件
Okinawa such widespread name recognition
冲绳如此广泛的知名度
often recognized as the bloodiest battle in the Pacific
通常被认为是太平洋上最血腥的战斗
the battle of Okinawa was also the longest
冲绳战役也是历时最长的一次
what would prove to be the last major
什么会被证明是最后一个主要的
battle before Japanese surrender
日本投降前的战斗
overtaking these islands so comparatively
超越这些岛屿
close to the Japanese mainland took months
靠近日本本土花了几个月的时间
making landfall in April of nineteen forty five
1945年4月登陆
us troops immediately took the
美军立即占领了
then Japanese Kadena air strip
然后是日本嘉手纳飞机跑道
with a foothold in the center of the island
在岛的中心有立足点
us troops based their assaults from the area
美军从该地区开始进攻
including the comandeered airbase  thus
包括被摧毁的空军基地
by the time Okinawa fell
到冲绳陷落的时候
then Japan soon surrendered
然后日本很快就投降了
the us had already set up operations on the island
美国已经在岛上部署了行动
as World War II gave way to American occupation of Japan
随着第二次世界大战让位于美国对日本的占领
and as the battle lines of the cold war began taking shape
随着冷战的战线开始形成
with an increasingly aggressive North Korea looking to unify
随着日益咄咄逼人的朝鲜寻求统一
its peninsula and a rising Chinese communist party
朝鲜半岛和崛起的中国共产党
Okinawa seemed a logical position to maintain a
冲绳似乎是一个合乎逻辑的立场
u s foothold from an American perspective
从美国的角度看美国的立足点
it made sense from a Japanese perspective too
从日本人的角度来看，这也是有道理的。
because of article nine of this document
因为本文件第九条
the nineteen forty five constitution of Japan
1945年日本宪法
the country could not make war nor maintain an army
这个国家既不能发动战争也不能维持军队
because of this treaty
因为这个条约
for someone to provide defense
为某人提供辩护
Japan would rely on the us
日本将依赖美国
allowing the us to maintain a presence within Japan
允许美国在日本保持存在
and because of article three in this treaty  Okinawa
因为冲绳条约第三条
should the us want to take it on
美国应该承担吗？
would no longer be administered by Japan
将不再由日本管理
but would rather be run solely by the United States
但宁愿由美国单独管理
by the terms of peace largely dictated
和平的条件在很大程度上决定了
to it from the rest of the world
从世界其他地方到它
Japan had no reason to push back on the
日本没有理由反击
us expanding its presence on Okinawa
美国扩大在冲绳的存在
it was no longer theirs
那不再是他们的了
and the bases on the island would
岛上的基地会
serve to protect their interests
保护他们的利益
for the now allied major world powers
对现已结盟的世界大国来说
it made sense to dot the strategically
在战略上点缀是有意义的
advantageous island with as many bases and
有利的岛屿，有尽可能多的基地和
military installations as it could bear
军事设施所能承受的
for those on the island  well
对于岛上的人
they didn't have much say
他们没有多少发言权
beyond the beaches and warm weather
超越海滩和温暖的天气
Okinawa's draw for tourists is its
冲绳吸引游客的地方是它
differences from the mainland
与大陆的差异
while Japanese today and part of Japan from
而今天的日本和日本的一部分来自
eighteen seventy nine to World War ii
1879年到第二次世界大战
Okinawans are proudly Okinawan
冲绳人自豪冲绳人
a distinct ethnicity that celebrates a history
庆祝历史的独特种族
and heritage unique to the ryukyu islands
琉球群岛特有的遗产
while Japan doesn't recognize the population as a minority
虽然日本不承认人口是少数民族
the un has recommended considering okinawans
联合国建议考虑冲绳人
as an indigenous group in order to begin
作为一个土著群体
protecting the local dialect and culture
保护地方方言和文化
in many ways
在许多方面
and after many centuries of intermingling
经过许多世纪的交融
there are plenty of similarities to the rest of Japan
与日本其他地方有许多相似之处
but given the island's largest
但考虑到岛上最大的
city is far closer to Shanghai
城市离上海更近
and Hangzhou
和杭州
and Taipei than to Tokyo
和台北，而不是东京。
there's plenty of Chinese influence too
中国也有很大的影响力
different food and a more laid back way of life
不同的食物和更悠闲的生活方式
has served to bring tourists in recently
最近吸引了很多游客
but such differences have also had a way of being
但这种差异也有其存在的方式
leveraged in the pursuits of bigger nations
在大国的追逐中举足轻重
the estimates vary
估计各不相同
but one hundred and fifty thousand is the common
但十五万是常见的
number cited when discussing how many Okinawans
讨论有多少冲绳人时引用的数字
either civilian or conscripted by Japan
平民或日本征兵
died in the battle of Okinawa
死于冲绳战役
making them the leading group in casualties
使他们成为伤亡人数最多的小组
stuck in the middle
卡在中间
both Japanese and American soldiers at points
日本士兵和美国士兵都在
committed atrocities towards the local population
对当地居民犯下暴行
once under American command
曾受美军指挥
there really wasn't much consideration
真的没有太多考虑
as to Okinawan interests either
关于冲绳人的利益
the island adopted the u s dollar
该岛采用美元
cars drove on the right side of the road
汽车在路的右边行驶
and as Korea and then Vietnam required more
随着韩国和越南的需求增加
and more attention and military resources
以及更多的关注和军事资源
the u s bases expanded across much of the
美国的基地扩大到大部分地区
island's most desirable flatlands
岛上最理想的平原
pushing a growing Okinawan population
推动冲绳人口的增长
to build denser and denser cities
建设越来越密集的城市
frustrated by the expanding presence and
对不断扩大的存在感到沮丧
comparatively slow economy to that of japan's
与日本经济相比相对缓慢
Okinawa pushed for a return to Japanese rule
冲绳推动日本回归统治
and in nineteen seventy two
在1972年
they got it
他们拿到了
but still a pacifist country by its constitution
但仍然是宪法规定的和平国家
and still reliant on the us for defense
仍然依赖美国进行防御
there was little reason for Japan to
日本没有理由这样做
question the size and quantity of the bases
质疑基地的大小和数量
and since then
从那以后
the status quo hasn't really changed
现状并没有真正改变
bases that boomed during the cold
在寒冷中隆隆作响的基地
war have right sized a bit
战争的规模有点合适
and some land has been returned here and there
到处都有土地被归还
but the map still looks like this
但地图还是这个样子
within these lines
在这些线内
some thirty thousand active military
大约三万名现役军人
members from all branches work
来自所有分支机构的成员工作
train and live
训练和生活
accompanying them are another fifty thousand
陪同他们的还有另外五万人
Americans that make living there full time possible
使在那里生活成为可能的美国人
the family members
家庭成员
the school teachers
学校老师
and the support staff working for forty
和40岁的支持人员
thousand dollars a year at the grocery store
在杂货店一年赚一千美元
or a hundred and ten thousand dollars as a
或者十万美元作为一个
principal at the elementary school
小学校长
and within the fences of the likes of Kadena air
在嘉手纳空气之类的栅栏内
base or camp foster or air station Futenma
基地或营地寄养或航空站普天间
there's far more than just the novelty fast
不仅仅是新奇快
food place or high school football stadium to
美食场所或高中足球场
remind one of the connection back to the us  rather
让人想起与美国的联系
these simply are the us
这些只是美国
with fully developed Pre k through twelfth grade educations
从学前教育到十二年级教育都得到充分发展
after school activity programs
课外活动项目
recreation centers
娱乐中心
exchanges that effectively serve as shopping malls
有效充当购物中心的交易所
suburban developments and single family homes
郊区开发和独栋住宅
these bases don't remind of America
这些基地不会让人想起美国
they simulate it
他们模拟它
and for those born on these bases including
对于那些出生在这些基地的人，包括
celebrities like Robert Griffin III or Zach Bryan
像罗伯特·格里芬三世或扎克·布莱恩这样的名人
they're not born with a dual
他们不是天生就有双重人格
citizenship or Japanese citizenship
国籍或日本国籍
they're born an American citizen
他们生来就是美国公民
but while fenced in
但在围栏中
these bases are permeable
这些基底是可渗透的
at least in one direction
至少在一个方向上
while Okinawans aren't welcomed into these bases
虽然冲绳人不被欢迎进入这些基地
the American stationed here pour
驻扎在这里的美国人
out onto the larger islands
到更大的岛屿上
with housing at a crunch
住房危机
service members are asked to live off base
服役人员被要求住在基地外
while those living on it are pushed to
而生活在上面的人被推到
explore the island when they're off work
在他们下班的时候探索这个岛
and this is where most problems originates
这是大多数问题的根源
if you've heard Okinawa mentioned in the news lately
如果你最近在新闻中听到冲绳
it's probably because of this video of a
可能是因为这个视频
military policeman brutally body slamming someone
宪兵残忍地身体猛击某人
who ultimately turns out to be an American
最终证明他是美国人
veteran over whom he had no legal jurisdiction
他没有法律管辖权的老兵
where this happened and why is informed by the
这发生在哪里，为什么由
uneasy overlap of two cultures and a set of
两种文化的不稳定重叠和一套
rules agreed upon in nineteen sixty
1960年商定的规则
the incident was on gate two streets where Kadena air base
事故发生在嘉手纳空军基地的两条街的大门
gives way to a section of Okinawa city littered with bars
让位于冲绳的一个酒吧区
and clubs frequented by those working at the base
和基地工作人员经常光顾的俱乐部
the individual was approached on this street in
这个人是在这条街上被接近的
the early morning hours and was demanded to show
凌晨时分，并被要求展示
identification by American military police
美国宪兵的身份证明
now the fact that MPs are patrolling off base
现在国会议员在基地外巡逻
to begin with may raise an eyebrow and
一开始可能会扬起眉毛
perhaps the concern of a local Okinawan
也许是当地冲绳人的担忧
but it's allowed because of the status of forces agreement
但这是允许的，因为部队地位协议
between Japan and the us which in this case provides that
在日本和美国之间，在这种情况下规定
MPs may patrol off base in special agreed upon circumstances
国会议员可以在特殊情况下在基地外巡逻
with jurisdiction only over us service members
仅对我们的服务成员有管辖权
and why the cops were out asking for
还有为什么警察在外面找你
identification was because off base service
识别是因为基地外服务
members are banned from drinking from one am to five am
会员从凌晨1点到5点禁止喝酒
this ban and subsequent patrol was in response
这项禁令和随后的巡逻是为了回应
to a set of domestic violence cases committed
一系列家庭暴力案件
by service members on local women
由当地妇女服务人员提供
the effort to curb late night drinking is
遏制深夜饮酒的努力是
not a new strategy on the islands
在岛上不是新策略
and crime and sexual assault by u s
以及美国的犯罪和性侵犯
service members is not a new problem
服务人员不是新问题
high profile sexual violence and murder
高调的性暴力和谋杀
cases followed by massive protests have
大规模抗议之后的案件
rocked the island in the nineteen nineties
在十九世纪九十年代震撼了这个岛
the twenty tens
二十元
and the twenty twenties
和二十年代
adding fuel to these massive flare ups is the locally
给这些大规模爆发火上浇油的是当地
held belief that only a small portion of sexual violence
认为只有一小部分性暴力
is fairly reported and subsequently tried by the
被公正地报道并随后由
Japanese and military legal systems on the island
岛上的日本和军事法律制度
they make a compelling point
他们提出了一个令人信服的观点
because of the same nineteen sixties status of
因为同样的20世纪60年代的地位
forces agreement between the two countries
两国军事协定
us forces on the island are uniquely protected
岛上的美军受到独特的保护
for crimes committed on base or on duty
对于在基地或执勤时犯下的罪行
the us has primary jurisdiction
美国有主要管辖权
and in these incidents
在这些事件中
the paper trail can get light
纸质线索可以得到光
through foia requests
通过foia请求
one reporter found that in pursuit of seven
一名记者发现在追捕七个
separate sexual assault investigations on the
单独的性侵犯调查
island from twenty seventeen to twenty nineteen
岛从二百一十七到二百一十九
none were made public
没有一个被公开
as for rest that happen off base and off duty
至于发生在基地和值班之外的休息
while these are pursued and tried
当这些被追求和尝试时
through japan's legal system
通过日本的法律体系
the us still has the right to consent to or withhold
美国仍然有权同意或拒绝
extradition if the service member made it back onto base
如果服役人员回到基地就引渡
even if apprehended off base
即使在基地外被捕
the service member can't be taken into
服务人员不能被带走
custody for questioning before prosecution  together
起诉前的羁押讯问
these protections make it far harder
这些保护措施让它变得更加困难
to build a case and prosecute
立案起诉
so Japan doesn't
所以日本没有
from two thousand one to twenty eighteen
从二千一到二百一十八
the prosecution rate for criminal offenses committed
刑事犯罪的起诉率
by u s military personnel was thirteen percent
美国军方人员占13%
compared to the forty four percent national rate
与全国百分之四十四的比率相比
because of a deal struck between
因为双方达成了一项协议
Japan and the u s six decades ago
六十年前的日本和美国
Okinawans feel like they're losing out on
冲绳人觉得他们正在失去
fair treatment in the justice system
司法系统中的公平待遇
leaving them uniquely vulnerable
让他们特别脆弱
if one major complaint is structural in a legal
如果一个主要投诉是结构性的
sense another is structural in the physical
感觉另一个是物质上的结构
a simple overhead shot makes it glaringly obvious
一个简单的头顶镜头让它变得非常明显
that the island's most important installations sit
岛上最重要的设施
right next to densely populated urban areas
紧邻人口稠密的市区
thus accidents occurring at one
因此事故发生在一个
are likely to impact the other
很可能会影响对方
that much was the case when a helicopter
当一架直升机
based at Futenma crashed into the next door
普天间基地撞上了隔壁
neighbor university in two thousand four
2004年的邻居大学
while no one died
虽然没有人死亡
Okinawans have protested base locations and their sheer
冲绳人抗议基地的位置和他们纯粹的
busyness over fear that the next accident will be the big
担心下一次事故会是大事故
one
一个
with eight crashes in and around the
有八起撞车事故
island in twenty sixteen alone
孤岛在二十六
with the arrival of the accident prone and much
随着事故的到来，容易发生
maligned MV twenty two osprey in twenty twelve
诽谤MV二十二鱼鹰在二十二
with the occasional helicopter part falling and
偶尔会有直升机部件坠落
landing on elementary school and decker properties
降落在小学和甲板上
locals think it's only a matter of time before luck runs
当地人认为走运只是时间问题
out and one of these many accidents turns into a tragedy
许多事故中的一个会变成悲剧
then there's the less dramatic but dangerous all the same
还有一个不那么戏剧化但同样危险的
pollution leaking from these military installations  again
这些军事设施再次泄漏污染
because of the nineteen sixties status of forces agreement
因为六十年代的部队地位协定
it's really difficult to get an exact picture
很难得到确切的图片
as to just how much pollution is emanating from
到底有多少污染来自
these bases and training facilities
这些基地和训练设施
because Japan's not allowed to check
因为日本不允许检查
only when a confirmed spill reaches a confirmed
只有当确认的泄漏到达确认的
volume can Japanese officials go in and inspects
日本官员可以进去检查吗？
but otherwise these bases are left to their own devices
但除此之外，这些基地只能靠自己了
but a freedom of information request from twenty
但是20岁的信息自由要求
sixteen has shed some light onto what exactly has been
16号揭示了过去到底发生了什么
spilled on the island since the nineteen nineties
自19世纪90年代以来一直在岛上
and it's a lot
而且很多
Diesel in twenty eleven and sewer in twenty thirteen
柴油在211，下水道在213
from cadina made its way to the Hija river which towns
从卡迪纳到希贾河，哪个城镇
in the base itself used for drinking water  pcbs
在用于饮用水的底座本身中多氯联苯
chemicals banned in the us in nineteen seventy nine
一九七九年美国禁止使用化学品
were improperly disposed of
被不当处理
somewhere around here in the seventies
七十年代这里的某个地方
and after being mentioned by a whistleblower
在被告密者提到后
sparked a testing program that found
引发了一个测试程序，发现
contamination across the base
整个基地的污染
finally  a revelation over chemical dumping in the
最后揭露了化学倾倒在
ravines around the base in the nineteen
十九世纪基地周围的沟壑
sixties came to light in the twenty tens
六十年代在二十年代出现
causing major concern for the residents nearby
引起了附近居民的极大关注
along with those sending students to these schools
以及那些把学生送到这些学校的人
while the official statements told
虽然官方声明说
residents that cleanup went well and that
清理工作进展顺利的居民
there's little to worry about going forward
没什么好担心的
one hundred and seven pages of test results
一百零七页的测试结果
were redacted within the Foia materials
在Foia材料中被编辑了
in addition to what's been dumped in
除了被倾倒的东西
the water and buried in the ground
水埋在地下
there's also the air and noise
还有空气和噪音
pollution that rocks the island too
污染也震撼了这个岛
as jet fuel fumes and the howl of f-35s
当喷气燃料烟雾和f-35的嚎叫
are just part of everyday life here
只是这里日常生活的一部分
but beyond what the us does at these bases
但除了美国在这些基地所做的
just the simple fact that they exist at such a scale
只是一个简单的事实，它们以如此大的规模存在
is a cause for major frustration to o'keeffe
是O'Keeffe非常沮丧的原因
one fifth of the entire island is
整个岛屿的五分之一是
taken up by the us military
被美军接管
and while the island is compensated for the land
虽然岛屿得到了土地补偿
the rent is fairly meager when one considers the
如果考虑到
economic potential for all this favorable flat land
所有这些有利的平坦土地的经济潜力
take this swath of land here
占领这片土地
since the fifties
五十年代以来
this was the awasi meadows golf course
这是阿瓦西草地高尔夫球场
according to the Americans who played it over the years
根据多年来演奏它的美国人的说法
it was busy  beautiful
它很忙，很漂亮。
and had an amazing and affordable
并有一个惊人的和负担得起的
restaurant in the clubhouse
会所内的餐厅
but returned back to the island
但回到岛上
the space serves a lot more
空间服务更多
there's a massive mall that hits ten million customers
有一个巨大的购物中心吸引了一千万顾客
there's high rise housing
有高层住宅
there's a hospital
有一家医院
all things that serve local needs
一切服务于当地需求的东西
and spur the local economy
并刺激当地经济
this isn't an isolated example either  in Naha
这在那霸也不是个孤立的例子
there used to be this
以前有这个
the ever dispersed Maki Minato housing project
一直分散的Maki Minato住宅项目
in nineteen eighty seven
一九八七年
it was returned back to Okinawa
它被退回冲绳了
and now it's a bustling commercial center with housing
现在它是一个有住房的繁华商业中心
museums  parks and shops
博物馆、公园和商店
a study taken on by the OCALA government in twenty fifteen
OCALA政府在二十五年进行的一项研究
calculated that the economic impact of the area as us
计算出该地区的经济影响为我们
housing produced thirty three million dollars and after
住房生产了3300万美元，之后
the commercial district had been established produced
商业区已经建立
about a billion dollars a thirty two fold increase
大约10亿美元增长32倍
American style Lane use anywhere is rather inefficient
美式车道在任何地方使用都相当低效
but on such a small island with such a massive population
但在这么小人口这么多的岛上
places like Cadena with its golf
像Cadena这样有高尔夫球场的地方
course and its sprawling Merrek park
球场及其庞大的Merrek公园
Washington heights
华盛顿高地
Stillwell park and Stirling heights neighborhoods
Stillwell公园和Stirling高地附近
represent the height of inefficiency
代表效率低下的高度
and a rent for such land
以及这种土地的租金
should it accurately reflect the land's value
它应该准确反映土地的价值吗？
would prove absurdly high
会被证明是荒谬的高
but there's little reason to think much is
但没什么理由认为
bound to change here anytime soon
这里一定会很快改变
while the exact contours of conflict and
虽然冲突的确切轮廓和
potential conflict in the far Pacific have changed
远太平洋的潜在冲突已经改变
the u s strategy remains remarkably similar to
美国的战略仍然非常相似
what it looked like in the nineteen fifties
二十世纪五十年代的样子
with the establishment of the island chain strategy
随着岛链战略的确立
where the u s would contain Asian communist powers
美国将在那里遏制亚洲共产主义大国
through strategically located Pacific island bases
通过位于战略位置的太平洋岛屿基地
split between two island clusters
分裂成两个岛群
Okinawa sits right on the northern
冲绳位于北部
edge of the first island chain
第一岛链边缘
and extremely close to the Chinese mainland
而且离中国大陆非常近
making the island feel increasingly central is China's
让这个岛屿感觉越来越中心是中国的
increasingly aggressive stance towards Taiwan
对台立场日趋强硬
with Guam the nearest American base to the island
关岛是离该岛最近的美军基地
Guam's role is not just to project
关岛的角色不仅仅是投射
American might in the region
美国在该地区的势力
but potentially be the first to provide it
但有可能成为第一个提供它的人
often referred to as the Keystone of the Pacific
通常被称为太平洋的基石
no matter the local frustrations
不管当地的挫折
over flyovers and pollution
天桥和污染
the only reason for Kadena to Shrink in size or
嘉手纳缩小尺寸或
stature would be one dictated by us military
身材将由美国军方决定
strategists in the context of China's maneuvering  again
中国再次机动背景下的战略家
leaving history to repeat itself
让历史重演
and leaving okinawaans to deal with
留下冲绳人去处理
repercussions of decision making by a faraway power
遥远大国决策的反响
of course
当然
as a Japanese prefecture populated by Japanese nationals
作为一个由日本国民居住的日本县
Japan has a say in Okinawa's land allocation
日本对冲绳的土地分配有发言权
but from a larger geopolitical standpoint
但从更大的地缘政治角度来看
their interests align with those of the
他们的利益与
us as do their security concerns
我们以及他们的安全担忧
from a defense perspective
从防御的角度来看
a bunch of bases far away from the mainland
一群远离大陆的基地
but near the region's biggest
但在该地区最大的
threats and potential conflict zones
威胁和潜在冲突区
is pretty optimal
是相当理想的
Japan hears Okinawan complaints and may even sympathize
日本听到冲绳的抱怨，甚至可能同情
but national security concerns
但是国家安全问题
outweigh the plight of the Islands  in fact
事实上超过了群岛的困境
rather than questioning bases on the main island of Okinawa  Japan
而不是质疑日本冲绳岛的基地
has begun positioning its own missiles on other Okinawan
已经开始在其他冲绳部署自己的导弹
Islands as their own military capabilities slowly grow
岛屿随着自身军事能力的缓慢增长
recently
最近
military activity on the island has signified that
岛上的军事活动表明
things may look different in the near future
在不久的将来，情况可能会有所不同
in November of 2025
2025年11月
the eighteenth air wing at Kadena
嘉手纳的第十八空军联队
undertook readiness exercise bh 261
进行了准备演习bh 261
the goal of the exercise was to test and through practice
练习的目的是测试并通过实践
speed up their ability to make runway repairs on the fly
加快他们在飞行中修理跑道的能力
in press releases
在新闻稿中
it was framed as a successful exercise
它被定义为一次成功的演习
from an okanagan perspective  though
从okanagan的角度来看
such an exercise is unsettling at best
这种做法充其量是令人不安的
preparing to repair runways is an implicit
准备修理跑道是隐含的
recognition that Kadena is no longer just the
认识到嘉手纳不再只是
forward operating base for the us air force in the region
美国空军在该地区的前沿作战基地
it's potentially also a first target
它也可能是第一个目标
not only does Okinawa remain at the mercy of the same
冲绳不仅仍然任由同样的事情摆布
large powers that fought over it in World War II
在第二次世界大战中为它而战的大国
it's increasingly within the crosshairs of a third
它越来越成为第三方的目标
for decades  the island has called for a change
几十年来，这个岛一直呼吁改变
things are in fact changing here
事实上，这里的情况正在发生变化
but not necessarily for the better
但不一定会好起来
what is only getting better as time goes on though
随着时间的推移，什么才会变得更好？
if i may say so myself
如果我可以这么说的话
is this season of jet lag the game  right now
这个时差季节是现在的游戏吗？
you can get caught up on season
你可以赶上季节
sixteen on the YouTube channel
YouTube频道上的16个
but if you want to get ahead
但如果你想出人头地
there's another way to watch
还有另一种观看方式
stay a week ahead and skip the
提前一周，跳过
ads by heading over to nebula
前往星云的广告
the sponsor of today's video
今天视频的赞助商
Nebula is a streaming platform founded by
星云是一个流媒体平台，由
creators for creators that has helped awesome
帮助真棒的创作者的创作者
projects like jet lag get off the ground
像时差这样的项目开始启动
and every day
每一天
Nebula's library gets a little bit deeper
星云的图书馆变得更深了
another exciting project that appears on Nebula is
星云上出现的另一个令人兴奋的项目是
Joe Scott's oldest and newest places on earth
乔·斯科特在地球上最古老和最新的地方
this takes Joe Scott out of the studio and into the
这把乔·斯科特带出工作室，进入
big wide world to explore some of the most unique
广阔的世界探索一些最独特的
geologic places this planet has to offer
这个星球的地理位置
making it not just educational but also
使它不仅具有教育意义，而且
blending elements of travel in too
融合了旅行的元素
whether it's projects like jet lag that release early on
无论是像时差反应这样的项目
the platform or nebula originals production heavy
平台或星云原件生产沉重
documentaries shows and even full length films that exist
纪录片甚至全长电影
only on the platform or simply the library from channels
仅在平台上或只是来自渠道的图书馆
like this one with early releases and no ads
就像这个提前发布没有广告的
if you're a fan of our content
如果您是我们内容的粉丝
or Joe Scott's
或者乔·斯科特的
or the dozens upon dozens upon dozens of other
或者几十个又几十个其他的
creators supporting and supported by Nebula
星云支持和支持的创作者
there's something on this platform for you
这个平台上有东西给你
across the board
一刀切
this platform has allowed us to all really push
这个平台让我们都真正推动
our boundaries and take on projects with bigger
我们的边界并承担更大的项目
production budgets and more creative risk
制作预算和更多创意风险
so i'm confident there is something in there for you
所以我相信里面有适合你的东西
and now's a great time to try it  right now
现在是尝试的好时机
you can get an annual subscription for fifty percent off
您可以以50%的折扣获得年度订阅
and thirty bucks spread across twelve
三十块钱分散在十二个人身上
months is just two fifty a month
一个月也就二百五十
that's a crazy deal
这是个疯狂的交易
so get to it by following the link in
所以按照链接进去就可以了
the description of this video
这个视频的描述